Guide to the Jane Lathrop Stanford Papers SC0033B
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Correspondence, 1868-1905; Series 1; 6 Linear Feet
  - Incoming
    - Incoming: Sta - Sti, 1891-1902 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Staubes, Chas., ALS Re. conditions at Vina Ranch., Aug 17, 1893
      - Steinman, B.U., Tel. congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - Stillman, Elizabeth G., ALS visit to Palo Alto, Apr 17 ?
      - Stillman, J.M., ALS, Mar 2, 1896 and Nov 15, 1901
      - Stillman, Leland, ALS, Jan 13, 1902 and May 20, 1902
    - Incoming: Sto - Sw, 1892-1896 (Box 8, Folder 29.1)
      - Stone, J. M., ALS, Sep 11, 1893
      - Stoner, Emma L., ALS, Nov 25, 1892 thanks for helping boy
      - Stranahan, Clara H., ALS, Oct 17, 1895
      - Strange, R., ALS, Mar 21, 1896
      - [Strobridge], [illegible], ALS, March 9, 1895
      - Swan, Louise S., ALS, Apr 2, 1893 and Mar 22, 1896
      - Swift, Carrie D.T., ANS, Mar 7, 1896
    - Incoming: Taylor, Agnes and Edward R., 1896-1898 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Taylor, Agnes Stanford (Mrs. E.R.), ALS re dream of Leland, July 16 [post 1893]
      - Taylor, Edward R., ALS congrats, Mar 4, 1896 and Mar 1896
      - Taylor, Edward R., re paying the legacy and fulfilling his duties as Trustee, May 30, 1898
    - Incoming: Thompson, Ellen F., 1895-1896 (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - ALS re gift of portrait to Roble Hall, Jan 15, 1895
      - Tel. congratulatory message, Mar 2, 1896
      - ALS campus rejoices; expresses her gratitude for Jane's work on behalf of the University, Mar 1896
    - Incoming: Towne, 1895-1896 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Towne, A. N., Tel., Jan 8, 1895
      - Towne, A. N., TLS re business advice, June 17, 1895
      - Towne, Caroline A. (Mrs. A. N.), ALS both congratulatory, Nov 1895 and Mar 1896
    - Incoming: Tweed, Charles H., 1900-1902 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - TLS re Huntington's death, 29-Aug-00
      - TLS re travel considerations for Dr. Heber Newton, March 3, 1902
      - TLS re travel considerations for Dr. Heber Newton, March 7, 1902
    - Incoming: Ta - Te, 1890-1902 (Box 8, Folder 34)
      - Taggert, Moses, ALS expresses appreciation for priceless gift, July 24, 1902
      - Tallmadge, Harriet W., ALS thanks for photos, Mar 27, 1890
      - Tanner, M. L., ALS, Sep 4, 1898
      - Teller, H.M. and J.R. Hawley, Tel., Mar 2, 1896
      - [Temberlake] Mrs. D.W., ALS invitation, 1895
      - Temple, D.H., ALS congratulations, daughter at Roble (gave Leland Jr. Bible lessons), Mar 9, 1896
    - Incoming: Th - Tu, 1893-1904 (Box 8, Folder 34.1)
      - Thomas, [?], TLS List of men discharched from Vina Ranch., Sep 5, 1893
      - Thompson, David A., ALS re. orphanage in Albany, 9-Dec-01
      - Thompson, William, ALS, 11-Dec-01
      - Thornton, James, ALS, Sep 18, 1893
      - Thurber, [illeg.] (sec. to U.S. Pres.), TLS thanks for Quad, June 15, 1895
      - Traveler, The, Tel. re. article on Leland Stanford, Aug 2, 1893
      - Tubbs, A.L., ALS, Sep 13, 1893 and Mar 4, 1896
      - Tucker, Frederick Booth, TLS and ALS, undated and Aug 9, 1904
    - Incoming: V, 1891-1897 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      - Valentine, John J. (Pres. Wells Fargo), TLS, Mar 3, 1896
      - Vance, [Florence] S., ALS invitation to stay at her home while in D.C., Jan 30, 1896
      - Van Orden, Emily, ALS re. payment of medical bills, May 24, 1893
      - Van Voast, James, TL to Wilson and Wilson acting for legatee Chas. Stanford, L.Stanford will, Jan 13, 1897
      - Vaughan, Sue L., ALS congratulations on opening of university and on monument to Father Junipero Serra, Oct 24, 1891
    - Incoming: W, 1890-1891 (Box 8, Folder 35.1)
      - Weir, Mrs. Andrew, ALS congratulations on opening of university, her own loss of a child, Nov 14, 1891
      - Wheeler, Sara, ALS congratulations on opening of university, Oct 31, 1891
      - Willey, William M., ALS re sending poem, May 5, 1890
      - Wood, Mary, ALS congratulations on opening of university, asks for RR pass for the bishop's parents, Oct 4, 1891
    - Incoming: Vivian, [Averil] (Mrs. H. Hussey), undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - ANS invitation, Jun 10
      - Jun 15
      - invitation for Duke's Reception, Jun 16
      - 2 cvrs.; calling cards of Mr. and Mrs. Vincenzo Botta in cvr., undated
    - Incoming: Western Granite and Marble Company, 1889-1891 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - ALS, have drawn up contract, Sep 25, 1889
      - ALS sending photos of the model for the statue of Fr. Serra, March 7, 1890
      - ALS delay encountered due to difficulties in transporting stone to San Jose, July 1, 1890
      - ALS statue is completed, May 13, 1891
      - ALS acknowledges receipt of check; needs further instructions for coping, June 25, 1891
      - AD copy of contract, Sep 25, 1889
      - photograph by Hill and Franklin: drawing of Fr. Serra?, undated
    - Incoming: White, Andrew D., 1893-1904 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - ALS introducing Margaret Wickham, Oct 3, 1893
      - ALS praising Jane for her handling of legal matters, July 13, 1895
      - TLS re his warm feeling for Stanford U. [with enclosed letter to Dr. Jordan Aug. 15, 1895]
      - TLS congratulations, praise for attorney Mr. Choate, Oct 16, 1895
      - TLS congratulations, Mar 3, 1896
      - TLS acknowledges photos, hopes she will build a hall in the Oxford sense, remembers meeting her son, is settled in Italy to do some writing, 13-Feb-03
      - TLS advice on needed buildings for Stanford U., March 17, 1904
    - Incoming: Whitlock, George, 1895 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - ALS thanking her for arranging for raise in wages; reminiscences of Leland, Jan 8, 1895
      - thanking her for sending Memorial Addresses on Leland Stanford, Jan 12, 1895
      - congratulations on suit, July 1, 1895
      - his pension was dropped again, Aug 13, 1895
      - congratulations on suit, Oct 13, 1895
    - Incoming: Wilson and Wilson, 1893-1902 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Letters are from Russell J. Wilson and/or Montford Wilson.
      - TLS re naming of legatees in Leland Stanford's will, July 5, 1893
      - TLS enclosing insurance check from Pacific Mutual Life ($11,784), Aug 9, 1893
      - TLS re claims for salaries of professors and employees on the Farm, Aug 14, 1893
      - TLS insurance copy wants acknowledgement, Aug 16, 1893
      - TLS sending letters re Chicago property, Aug 22, 1893
      - TLS sending agreement, Aug 25, 1893
      - TLS to Levi Maish re: lease of 1701 K St. in D.C., June 8, 1895
      - Tel. congratulations, Oct 12, 1895
      - TL encloses copy of agreement re Pacific Improvement Company [includes entire agreement dated Mar. 24, 1894 and an amendment dated Mar. 30, 1894], May 9, 1896
      - TLS sending items as requested, Jan 19, 1897
      - 2 TLS re indentures, deed of house and contents, Feb 16, 1897
      - TLS received her two letters, Mar 25, 1899
      - TLS will bring the document next Thursday, March 20, 1900
      - ALS and cvr. renew engagement for legal work for another year, Apr 9, 1900
      - TLS re health of Russell Wilson, Feb 21, 1902
    - Incoming: Wa - Wh, 1871-1902 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Walery [Photographie Walery], ALS and TLS with invoice, Aug 24, 1901 and Dec 1, 1901
      - Wallischeck, Peter, ALS, 2-Aug-02
      - Walter, Carrie Stevens, ALS personal news, "red flag of anarchy", July 10, 1894
      - Walter, Carrie Stevens, Mar 2, 1896
      - Walworth, Ellen Hardin, ALS, Aug 25, 1895
      - Warren, Minton,ALS re. Professor Pease, April 16, 1902
      - Washington, Mrs. Carter, ALS (fragment?) personal news, Christian Science, July 1, 1895
      - Watson, B.J., ALS, June 29, 1895
      - Weed, Thurlow, LS introduction for Victoria Andres, Sep 7, 1871
      - Wetherbee, Nellie M., ALS, Sep 13, 1894
      - Wheeler, Benj. I., thanks her for erecting chapel, 25-Sep-02
      - Wheeler, Zella Lentillian, ALS congratulations, sightseeing in New England, Mar 4, 1896
      - White, Ann Eliza, ALS personal news and congratulations, Jan 13, 1893; Oct 13, 1895; Mar 3, 1896
      - White Star Line, ALS, March 7, 1900
      - Whittell, Mrs. A.P., AN sends photos of Sisson's, undated
    - Incoming: Wi, 1891-1903 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Wickham, Margaret Mary, ALS, Mar, 1896
      - Wier, Jennie E., Tel., Mar 2, 1896
      - Wight, E. B., ALS, July 12, 1893
      - Wight, J.K., ALS Metropolitan Museum casts of classic sculpture, Oct 13, 1895
      - Wilcox, Ella Wheeler, ALS and TLS, Oct 2, 1903 and Apr 7, 1903
      - Wilder, A.D., Tel., Mar 2, 1896
      - Wilkinson, Mary M., ALS personal news, Mar 28, 1895
      - Williams, Clara, ALS, Mar 2, 1896
      - Williams, Cornelia S.U. (Mrs. Geo. B.), ALS, July 1, 1895
      - Williams, W. D., TLS, Dec 27, 1892
      - Wilson, Emily J., ALS thanks, Jan 25, 1895
      - Wilson, Emily J., roses and congratulations, undated
      - Wilson, J. B., ALS, July 25, 1893
      - Wilson, John A.B., ALS, Mar 2, 1896
      - Wilson, Walter H., TLS [with enclosure from Chas Shillaber and reply], Aug 1, 1893
      - Winchester, Col. R., ALS encloses poems, Nov 5, 1893
      - Winslow, Ellen T., ALS death of husband, Mrs. Hearot, Mar 7, 1891
      - Winslow, Ellen T., Mar 12, 1896
    - Incoming: Wr - Y, 1893-1902 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Wright, E. C., TLS Sends list of stockholders of S. P. Co., Jan 17, 1899
      - Wright, E. L., ALS, Oct 17, ny
      - Wright, Jane A., ALS re Leland Wright being named for Leland Stanford, Sep 14, 1893
      - Wykert, Leland Stanford, ALS, 21-Oct-02
      - Young, J. Lundley Murray, ALS, Mar 7, 1896
      - Younkin, Samual, ALS, Sep 1, 1893
    - Incoming: unidentified correspondents; fragments (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Begging letters, circa 1901
    Letters from individuals or groups asking for gifts or loans of money for selves, children, churches, charities, etc., or for jobs, scholarships, items for sale, etc. From all over the U.S., Canada, Mexico, Italy, Germany, England, Russia, France, Ireland and Spain.
    - A (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Ba-Bis (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Bit-Bu (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - C (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - D (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - E (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - F (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - G (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - H (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - I - J (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - K (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - L (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - M (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - N (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - O (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - P - Q (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - R (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Sa-Si (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Sl-Sw (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - T (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - U - V (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Wa-Wi (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Wi-Wo (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - X - Z (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Condolence letters
    - Re: the death of Anna Lathrop Hewes, 1892 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Includes Mrs. J.C. Burnett, Sarah B. Cooper (3), Mrs. Timothy Hopkins, Maria W. Judson, Louise La Montagne, Mrs. Mac Kenzie, Mrs. Mc Neill (housekeeper of J. L. Stanford in Sacramento), Col. [Marius?], Mamie Lavinia Meagher, May J. Meeks, Amelia V.R. Pixley (Mrs. Frank), and Edw. G. Thurber.
    - Re: the death of Leland Stanford, 1893
      - A, includes C.B. and Harriet Alexander, Bertha K. [Ankam], and Alice Archer-Hornblow (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Ba - Bi, includes Juliette M. Babbitt (Mrs. Chas. H), Alexander Badlam, Mrs. J.H. Bankhead, Mary S. Barnes, Luther F. Beecher (married the Stanfords), [Z.] W. Berryman, and Albert Bierstadt (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Bl - Br includes Jas. G. Blaine, Jr. (Tel.), Henry W. Blair, John Bonness, J.H.C. Bonté, F.O. Boyd, and John Boyd (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Bu - By includes Mary E. Bucknall, Fanny B. Houghton Bulkeley, Bell Parker Burns (see Century Club of Calif.), J.G. Butler, and Jennie Stanford Byington (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Ca includes M.C. [Cading], Louise Marriner Campbell, J.D. Carr, Wm. B. Carr, M.C.W. Carter, Charlotte Castle, and Clara L. Catherwood (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Ch - Cl includes O.B. Cheney, Sister Clare, J.N. Clements (Cazenovia Seminary), Endora Miller Clover, and Lewis P. Clover (friend of Lincoln) (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Co - Cu includes Anna Ewing Cochran, Michael Conlan, Cyrus Cooper, Sara B. Cooper, G.H. Corey, Dot Covert, Ethel Sperry Crocker, George Crocker, Julia A. Crocker, and Mary Crocker (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Da - De includes Madeline Vinton Dahlen, C.E. Daily (Comissioner for King Tebureimoa of Butaritari, Gilbert Is.), Anna Agnew Davis, Horace Davis, Anna L. Dawes, E.S. Dawes, Noble E. Dawson, and Lucy A.H. Deady (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Di - Du includes Melissa P. Dodge (Mrs. Wm. E), Sister Dolores, and Robert W. Douthat (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - E - F includes Adeline M. Easton, Margaret Edes, George F. Edmunds, Morris M. Estee, W.W. Evans, Leila Johnson Ewing, W.W. Faris, Stephen J. and Sue V. Field, and George Frere Flint (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Ga - Gw includes Julia R. Garniss, Grace H. Gilmor, George Goddard, Sarah Vail Gould, Julia D. Grant (Tel.), U.S. Grant, Jr., Anna Guthridge, and Wm. M. Gwin (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Ha includes Harry O. Hall (with poem), [F?] S. Hamlin, Jean Hanen, Benjamin Harrison, and Susan M. Harvey (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - He - Hi includes Phebe A. Hearst, David Hewes, E.E. Hewitt, Jennie E. Hill, and Nellie Adelaide Hillyer (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Ho - I includes Alex Hogg, Susan M. Holbrook, Timothy and May Hopkins, Thomas H. Hubbard, John F. Hurst, Frank [Hutton], Ida M.F. Iles, Anna Louisa Ingalls, Ethel Ingalls, and William Innis (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - J includes C.H. Johnson, Georgina S. Jones, David S. and Jessie Knight Jordan, Albert L. Judson, and Anna Juduh (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - K includes John J. Keane, Peter C. Kellogg, Maude Stanford Kinmouth, Elizabetha R. Kiplinger, Lucretia Wolcott Knowlton, and Mrs. J.H. Kyle (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - L includes Louise La Montagne, Julius Lansburgh, Lathrops, Jeannie Lathrop Lawton, S.V. Leech, Sister Lidwine, Jeanie Gould Lincoln, Mrs. Lippincott (Grace Greenwood), Mrs. John A. Logan, John A. Logan Jr., and Harriet M. Lothrop (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Mac - Mc includes Helena Mc Carthy, John B. Mc Carthy, Edward M. Mc Cook, Frank Mc Coppin, John W. Mac Kay (Tel.), Mary Harrison Mc Kee, and Emily Beales Mc Lean (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Mad- Men includes Jerome Madden, O.B. Mahone, and Margaretta Manning (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Mer - Mu includes Justin S. Merrill, Nelson A. Miles, Frank Miller, and Adelaide Murphy (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - N includes Mrs. A. E. Newman, John P. Newman, Mary P. Nimmo, and Joseph A. Nunez (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - O - P includes Palo Alto Stock Farm Employees, Alma A. Park, Geo. C. Perkins, Mary Pittenger, Amelia V.R. Pixley, Edith Taylor Pope, and Wm. H. Pratt (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - R includes A. J. Ralson, Whitelaw Reid (Tel.), Sallie J. Rickey, D. (?) Riordan, Matias Romero, and Mrs. Albert E. Ross (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Sa - Sh includes P. Scanlon, J.M. Schofield (Tel.), Irving M. Scott, Jessie D. Carr Seale, Searles, Henrietta J. Selby, Harriet A. Shafter, Albert Shaw, Frank Shay, Anne A. Shellabarger, M.E.W. Sherwood, and Daniel Shields (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Si - Sp includes Sisters of Charity (St. Vincent's Institute, Santa Barbara), Sisters of the Holy Cross (St. Mary's Academy, Alexandria, Va.), Sisters of Mercy (St. Joseph's Convent, Sacramento), Sisters of Notre Dame (Redwood City, San Jose, Wn. D.C.), W.R. Smedburg, Jos. F. Smith (and Wilford Woodruft, George Q. Cannon - 1st Presidency of Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints), N.T. Smith, Society of California Pioneers (N. Milner), Maurice Soule, and E.N. Spinola (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - St - Sw includes Stanford family (Jane E. Stanford, Thomas Welton Stanford, and others), Stanford Faculty, Horatio Stebbin (Tel.), John N. Stewart, Clara Stoltenberg, and Joseph Swain (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - T includes Mrs. T.W. Tallmadge, H.M. Teller, Emma H. Tillotson, Lily Rosecrans Toole, A.N. Towne, Nellie L. Treat, Kate Trowbridge, and E.C. Tubbs (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - U - We includes J.J. Valentine, Rosa Wallach, John and Mary B. Wanamaker, J.H. Warnick, Alice C. Waterman (S. F. Council of Women), and Nora Stanford Wells (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Wh - Z includes Andrew D. White, Ann Eliza White, Stephen M. White (Tel.), Geo. H. Whitlock, Blanche Whitwell, H.I. Willey, Emily J. Wilson, amd Ellen T. Windom (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Unidentified: ALS from unnamed Stanford student; tel. with indecipherable name (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Mrs. Stanford's letters (typescript copies), 1892-1905 (Box 13)
    Typescript copies of letters, primarily from J. L. Stanford to David Starr Jordan and primarily concerning the University; there is also an introductory essay on Jane L. Stanford by H. C. Nash, 1887. Also includes several excerpts from her journal of 1892 [which J. L. Stanford later destroyed].
- Business and legal papers, 1876-1908; Series 2; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Included in this series are bank books; bills, receipts, and accounts; stock, bonds, reports, and other records pertaining to railroad investments and the Pacific Improvement Company; papers pertaining to the estate of Leland Stanford; and miscellaneous property records.
  - Bank book from Metropolitan Trust (New York), 1899-1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bank book from Nevada Bank, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bank books from Union Trust (San Francisco), 1900-1902 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bank book from Wells Fargo, 1894-1901 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bills, receipts, and accounts, 1881-1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bills re: shipment of marble pillars, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cancelled checks, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Government Suit - clippings, 1894-1895 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Guatemala Central Railroad Company, see also Pacific Improvement Co., 1908 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Typed copies of resolutions, reports, and correspondence of Thomas H. Hubbard, D.B. Hodgson, and W.P. Tisdel.
  - Income and Property, 1893-1900 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Annual Income of Jane Stanford from interest on bonds, undated
    - Annual Income from Bonds: Jane Stanford, Thomas W. Stanford, LSJU, 20-Jan-00
    - Account of income from RR stocks/bonds for, 1893, 1894
    - Account of income for Jane L. Stanford, year of, 1899
    - Description of real estate owned by J. L. Stanford in Sacramento, undated
    - Description of real estate owned by J. L. Stanford and real estate deed to Board of Trustees, 1-Feb-00
  - Market Street Cable Railway Company, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - tel. to Charles G. Lathrop re electing Mr. Gage a director to replace Gov. Stanford, July 15, 1893
    - tel. to Wilson and Wilson Mrs. Stanford wants Charles Lathrop to replace Gov. Stanford on the Board, July 17, 1893
  - Mexican Railroad Bonds, 1897-1900 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Statements, resolutions, notes re bonded indebtedness of Mexican International Railroad Co.
  - Misc. Business Papers, 1876-1893 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Memoranda of RR bonds held by Arial Lathrop for J. L. Stanford, 1887
    - Power to Charles Lathrop to employ and dismiss employees at Vina or Palo Alto, Feb 8, 1895
    - Letters re business matters of a Mr. Alfred Poett, 1876-78
    - Two letters to J. C. Bradley from Tunis and Jacobs re title searches, 1887
    - Two letters re Russian horses to be exchanged for Palo Alto Stock Farm horses, 1893 Jul, Sep
  - Pacific Improvement Co.: Bay District Land Company, 1897-1900 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Correspondence of Richard Derby, C.E. Green, H. Shainwald, and A. S. Baldwin re property values.
  - Pacific Improvement Co. correspondence and notes, 1899-1900 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Dictation by Russell J. Wilson re PI Co. matters, Nov 2, 1899
    - Thomas H. Hubbard to William Mahl re settlement with P. I. Co., Sep 8, 1898
    - Thomas H. Hubbard to Russell J. Wilson with statement re indebtedness of PI Co., Nov 24, 1899
    - C. P. Huntington to Thomas H. Hubbard re Derby elected secretary of PI Co., 16-Apr-00
    - C. P. Huntington to Thomas H. Hubbard re wants to do something for Mrs. Douty, 23-Apr-00
    - Tel. C. P. Huntington to Thomas H. Hubbard re sale of PI Co. properties, May 2, 1900
    - C. P. Huntington to Charles G. Lathrop, with copy of his letter to Hubbard, May 1, 1900, re sale of Oakland properties of PI Co., May 2, 1900
    - Notes (in J.L. Stanford's hand) re. her dealings with the Pacific Improvement Co. (torn in 4 pieces), undated
  - Pacific Improvement Co. documents, 1894-1903 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - By-laws, 1900
    - Memo of securities advanced the PI Co for use as collateral, Mar 19, 1896
    - Associates Accounts, 1893-1896
    - Agreement between PI Co. and J. L. Stanford, Mar 27, 1894
    - Indenture between J. L. Stanford and George E. Crothers re PI Co. stock, Aug-03
    - Account: San Francisco Bills Payable, 31-Mar-00
    - Account: PI Co. to estate of Leland Stanford, 1896
    - Account: PI Co. notes bearing endorsement of Jane L. Stanford, 1894-1895
  - Permission to leave California after Leland's death, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Seale v. Ward, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Henry W. Seale vs. Thomas Ward Defendant's Brief re: Rancho Rinconado del Arroyo de San Francisquito (Mex. grant to Meza 1841); Rancho San Francisquito Palo Alto (Mex. grant to Buelna 1839).
  - Southern Pacific Company - letter from A.N. Towne to T. E. Stillman, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Stanford, Leland, estate matters, 1893-1898 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - bill of John B. McCarthy to estate for services as private secretary, 1893 Jul 13
    - notice of stockholders meeting, 1893 Aug 22
    - TDS to Legatees under Leland Stanford's Will. Status of suit; payments in kind; claims paid; values of estate., 1895 July 25
    - Statement of payments to legatees under will of Leland Stanford, 1897 Feb 26
    - Executrix's Final Account, Report and Petition for Final Distribution, 1898 Dec
  - Wells Fargo and Co. Express Shippers, Forwarding Receipt Book (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Personal and miscellaneous papers, 1872-1952; Series 3; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Series Descriptions
  These papers include passports, social invitations and calling cards, travel ephemera including a rental agreement for a Nile river boat (1901), commemorative poetry, and clippings.
  - Agreement on rental of boat for trip on Nile, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Calling cards (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Calling Lists, San Francisco and Washington, DC, 1892 and undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bound volume list of visitors in San Francisco, undated
    - Washington D.C. Calling list, 1892
  - Greeting card: "Fleurs de Gethsemani," Jerusalem, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Includes pressed flowers; sent by J. L. Stanford to her sister.
  - Honolulu - dinner menu and clipping, 1902-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Invitations, 1872-1891 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Kindergartens in San Francisco: account book, mostly empty, 1884-1885 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Includes memorial plaque inscriptions for Church, lease and purchase of shares in Professors Club House, printed invitation for reception for Bishop and Mrs. Newman, Passenger list "S.S. China" 1902, invitations, menus, contract for trip, passenger lists, place card, F.A. Robbins ALS 1905 with photo of J.L.Stanford's funeral procession, notes, poems, seating chart, news clippings of laces, clipping on ship "Jane L. Stanford", notes, membership list, and radio script.
  - Passports, 1883-1902 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - TLS John Sherman to J. L. Stanford, Aug 10, 1897
    - TLS John Hay introducing J. L. Stanford, 25-Apr-00
    - TLS John Sherman introducing J. L. Stanford, May 21, 1897
    - TLS Geo. C. Perkins to J. L. Stanford, 26-Apr-00
    - TLS John Hay to Geo. C. Perkins, 25-Apr-00
    - passport of J. L. Stanford s. Edward F. Noyes, Dec 9, 1880
    - passport of J.L.Stanford, L.Stanford, and L.Stanford, Jr. s. Alphonso Taft, Dec 29, 1883